Atul Meshram

Product Designer

🕑 🛮 Bangalore, Karnataka - INDIA





Education

- **Interaction Design Specialization** University of California, San Diego 9.9 Score | Jan. 2018 | Coursera
- **Master of Computer Applications** NIT Karnataka, Surathkal 8.5 CGPA | May, 2016
- **GNIIT Software Engineering NIIT**

Grade - A | Apr. 2013

- **Bachelor of Computer Applications** PRSU, Raipur 78.0% | Jun, 2011
- Class 12th (Senior Secondary Edu.) **CBSE - All India** 81.0% | May, 2007

Skills

Design Tools

Sketch InVision Studio Figma Adobe XD

Adobe After Effects FramerX ProtoPie Adobe Illustrator

Flinto Blender

User Experience

User Research Motion Design Wireframing Visual Design Rapid Prototyping **Heuristic Evaluation** Visual Design **Usability Testing** Interaction Design Comparative Analysis

Programming

JavaScript (ES6) **ThreeJS GSAP** HTML5 CSS3 VueJS

ReactJS

Leadership

Project Planning UX Strategy & Planning Team Coordination Training & Mentorship

Summary

A product designer having 4 years of design experience with interests in immersive design and extended reality-based emerging technologies. I enjoy interacting with people to understand their expectations and unpleasant experiences from the products and I use their insights to create simple and beautiful interfaces that have a high degree of usability.

Experience

o9 Solutions

Bengaluru, IN

Senior Product Designer

[MAY, 2018 - Present]

Designed and prototyped dozens of widgets and features for web, mobile, and desktop applications that varied from small, one-week prototypes that explored specific interactions to large-scale, multi-month projects targeted for the launch.

Designed an intuitive, interactive, and smart analytical visual interface for AI-based smart supply-chain platform offering features like:

Natural Language Search, Rich Data Visualization, Real-Time Collaboration, Connected Excel, Mobile Experience, Integrated Email, Geo Map & Network, Online Meeting and Presentation, and Favorite Management.

Case Study: https://atulmeshram.github.io/o9-solutions.html

Accolite Software

Bengaluru, IN

UX Designer

[JUL, 2016 - MAR, 2018]

Worked with multiple clients at client locations. Analyzed, prototyped, and delivered the designs as per the client's needs and requirements.

Standard Chartered Banking App

[NOV, 2017 - MAR, 2018]

A mobile app that allows you to see, move and manage your finances anytime, anywhere. I designed UI to offer UPI based transactions to facilitate safe, easy & instant digital payments through the mobile phone.

Google Play Store: https://cutt.ly/ryNkoPX

FedEx FRMS iPad App

[SEP 2017 - NOV 2017]

An iPad App for FedEx's Pilot Fatigue Management. Analyzed existing web application and redesigned the workflow for the iPad app. Designed high-fidelity clickable prototypes. Done UI design assets distribution, application flow, animations, and design guide for developers.

BT Business App

[JUL 2016 - OCT 2017]

A mobile application providing all business services to users offering features to view bills, check accounts, test broadband speed, track orders and faults, provide free wi-fi and internet.

Interacted, analyzed, and interpreted customer needs to create a pleasant user experience. Designed application flow, created wireframes, and high-fidelity mock-ups.

Google Play Store: https://cutt.ly/8yNkbU2 Apple App Store: https://cutt.ly/kyNkRFY